forexroot.com 2012-05-09

# Privacy Policy | Forex Root

**Introduction**

At **Forex Root** our most important asset is our relationship with you.  Therefore, we are committed to safeguarding the privacy of the personally identifiable information we collect from you via this website (the “Site”).

Your information is yours and we respect that.  This policy outlines the types of information **Forex Root** collects about you and how that information is used.  The policy applies to all current and former members of **Forex Root**.  This policy may be revised from time to time, so please revisit this page often to remain fully informed of our policies.

We take precautions to ensure the information we collect about you is protected and is accessed only by authorized individuals and organizations.  Specifically, we follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personally identifiable information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it.  No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however.  Therefore, while we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your personally identifiable information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

Because we know how important security and privacy is to you, **Forex Root** operates under the following principles when handling your personal information:

We allow you to create a screen name that is not your real name, providing you control of identifying information within the **Forex Root** community.

You can de-activate your account for any reason at any time and we will delete all of your personally identifiable information from our servers. We will not keep a copy of your personally identifiable information for any purposes upon account deactivation except as may be required by law or to otherwise protect legal rights.

We use secure server software (SSL) and firewalls to protect your information from unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, or destruction. Further, our employees and third party service providers have access to your nonpublic personal information only on a “need to know” basis. Finally, we internally audit our business practices and procedures, examining confidentiality standards and information access in order to protect your personal information.

**What Information We Collect**  
**Personally Identifiable Information**

When you browse the non-password protected portions of our Site, you do so anonymously; no personally identifiable information is collected.  When you sign up to become a registered user of **Forex Root** we request that you provide to us your name, address and email address.

You may also choose to supply trading information (e.g., how long you have been trading, your preferred trading hours, etc.) and a profile description. Once you register with **Forex Root** and sign in to our Site, you are not anonymous to us. We may use the Registration Information to open an account with us, to provide services that may be useful to you and to contact you.

Our Site also permits you to contact us via email and our Contact Us form.  Whenever you send an email via our Site or through the Contact Us form, you will be providing us with your name, email address and any information you choose to include in the text of your message.  For example, you may choose to provide your mailing address or other information necessary or helpful for us to address your query or concern.

In addition, as a registered user of our Site, we collect and maintain information about your membership activity.  This activity includes your trading ideas, executed transactions, positions, history, comments, subscriptions to other members as well as ratings of other members’ trading ideas and comments and their ratings of you.  We publish this information and derivatives based on this information on our Site and we use this information to provide the services you have requested.

**Additional Personal Information You Provide, or Direct Us to Collect from Others, to Use our Service**

We also collect personal information from you in two other general ways:

  * Personal information you directly provide or input as you use the **Forex Root** Site; and
  * Personal information we gather with your permission from third party websites and Internet services that you register on our Site.

For example, once you are a registered user of our Site, you may register your brokerage account through our Site by providing the user ID, password and other information necessary to access such account (“Verification Information”).  We will collect the transactional information regarding your brokerage account to display it to you on the Site. This information may include your current holdings, and your past and future transactions, to name a few.

**Forex Root** limits its use of your personal investment information to the purposes for which it has been collected and as we describe in this Privacy Policy. Except as necessary to carry out your requests, **Forex Root** uses this information only on an aggregate, non-personal basis.

**Technical and Other Information**

When you visit our platform, we may collect information through “cookies” or other similar Web tools to enhance the user experience.  Cookies are small strings of text that are sent by our Site to your browser on your computer’s hard drive.  Cookies enable us to recognize you when you return to our Site, to maintain your Web session while you browse throughout the Site, as well as help us provide you with a better, more personalized experience. Our cookies are not tied to personally identifiable information.  Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but it is possible to change your browser setup so that it does not accept cookies.  However, rejecting cookies may prevent you from taking advantage of certain portions of our Site.  
In addition, when you are browsing our Site, **Forex Root** automatically receives and records information on our server logs from your browser including your IP address, **Forex Root** cookie information and the pages you request.  We use this information to improve the functionality and usability of our services.  Our log files are not tied to personally identifiable information.

**How We Use the Information We Collect**

**Communications from the Site**

We will send you strictly service-related announcements on rare occasions when it is necessary to do so.  For instance, if our Site is temporarily suspended for maintenance, we might send you an email.  Generally, you may not opt-out of these communications, which are not promotional in nature.

**Customer Service**

Based upon the personally identifiable information you provide us during the registration process, we will send you a welcoming email to verify your username and password.  We will also communicate with you in response to your inquiries, to provide the services you request, and to manage your account. 

We will communicate with you by email or telephone, in accordance with your wishes.

**Verification Information**

As a registered user of our Site, you provide to us your Verification Information to access your trading records from your Broker.  Verification Information is only used to verify the activity information and is not accessible anywhere on our Site.

**Information Sharing and Disclosure** **We Do Not Reveal Any Personally Identifiable Information**

We will not publish any personally identifiable information (e.g. name, email address or contact information) on our platform or Site for others to view, without your permission, unless you choose to post it yourself on the Site.

**We Do Not Reveal Any Verification Information**

We do not publish any verification information anywhere.  This is used solely in order to retrieve your trading data and is kept in strict accordance with our Terms of Use.

**You Choose to Whom You Want to Make Your Performances Public**

You may choose to whom you provide authorization to explore your trading performance, if any: your Virtual Trading Team members and/or for all **Forex Root** ‘s members.  Other registered users will be able to search for, access and review this information.

Should you elect to make your trading performance public to all **Forex Root** ‘s registered users, summary information including recent activity information may be made available to non-registered users and accessible by search engine technologies.

**We Do Not Rent or Share Any Personally Identifiable Information**

**Forex Root** does not rent or share any personally identifiable information with third parties that are not our agents or service providers, except as described in this privacy policy or, otherwise, with your permission.

**We May Provide Your Information If Legally Required**

**Forex Root** may be required to provide your information under the following circumstances: in response to subpoenas, court orders, or legal process, or to establish or exercise our legal rights or defend against actual or threatened legal claims.  In addition when we believe it is necessary to share information in order to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities or activities which we believe give rise to legal liability to us, our members or third parties, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person, violations of **Forex Root** ’s terms of use, or as otherwise required by law.

**Links to Other Sites**

Our Site may reference or provide links to other websites that are not owned or controlled by **Forex Root**. Please be aware that **Forex Root** does not control, nor are we responsible for, the privacy policies or information practices of such other websites.  This privacy policy applies only to information collected by this platform.

**Invite-A-Friend**

Our Site empowers you with insights into your trading information and enables you to connect with other traders by providing the names and email addresses of others whom you would like to invite to our Site. This information is used only to send your invitation and reminders.

If you choose to use our referral service to tell a friend about our Site, we will ask you for your friend’s name and email address.  We will automatically send your friend an email inviting him or her to visit our Site. **Forex Root** stores this information for the sole purpose of sending this one-time email and tracking the success of our referral program.

**Amending Your Account Information**

**Accuracy of Information**

We are committed to keeping accurate and up-to-date records to help ensure the integrity of the services we offer.  It is your responsibility, however, to ensure that such information is accurate, complete and up-to-date.  If you identify an inaccuracy, or need to make a change to any personally identifiable information you have provided to us, please update the information directly on our Site.  Alternatively, you may Contact Us to have such information changed.  If you believe any information to be erroneous, you can contact **Forex Root** and we will endeavor to verify and correct it if erroneous.  You may not change any information on the system regarding, or posted by, other people, including comments they make about you or your information.

**You Can Terminate Your Membership at Any Time**

You may terminate your **Forex Root** membership at any time by contacting us directly.  You can request your registration, activity and verification information be removed from our systems, and our security partners’ systems, and all data will be removed, subject to any legal requirements to keep it.  Comments added to other members’ blog posts may remain but will no longer be attributable to you.  Certain information may remain anonymously within aggregated data sets, and portions may remain in our archived records (pursuant to certain legal requirements) after your account has been deleted, as well as remain on third party systems we do not directly control.

**A Word About Public Profiles**

Our public profile feature allows you to publish portions of your **Forex Root** profile, including your member screen name but NOT your email address to the public. You have the ability to choose which personal information about you may be viewed by others. The account settings, tools and controls enable you to manage access to your personal information, portfolio information and your network and contacts.

**Journals, Comments and Posts**

If you write a journal post, a comment or a note on this Site, you should be aware that any personally identifiable information you submit there may be read, collected, or used by other users of these forums for communication, and could be used to send you unsolicited messages. We are not responsible for the personally identifiable information you choose to submit.

**Changes to This Privacy Policy**

**Forex Root** may update this policy at any time.  However, we will notify you of significant changes in the way we treat personally identifiable information by sending a notice to your email address or by placing a prominent notice on this section of our Site.  In the event **Forex Root** should be acquired by or merged with another company, your personally identifiable information and/or technical information we obtain from you via this Site may be disclosed to any potential or actual third party purchasers or may be among those assets transferred.

**Opt Out**

You may opt out of receiving communications from us and our affiliates by following the opt-out link provided in any email received from us or by emailing us [directly](mailto:support@forexroot.com).

**Consequences of Not Providing Information**

You may choose not to provide us with your personally identifiable information.  However, choosing not to provide certain requested personally identifiable information may prevent you from accessing and taking advantage of certain services offered by **Forex Root**.

**Children**

In compliance with the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act, 15 U.S.C. §§ 6501-06 and 16 C.F.R. §§ 1.1-1.1, our Site does not permit children under 18 years of age to become users, and we do not collect information from children.  By using our Site, you represent that you are not under 18 years of age.

**Acceptance of These Terms**

This Privacy Policy is incorporated into and subject to the terms of the **Forex Root** Terms of Use.  If you do not agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy, please do not provide us with any information and do not use this Site.  By using this Site and voluntarily providing your personally identifiable information to us, you consent to the collection and use of such personally identifiable information as set forth in this Privacy Policy.

**Effectiveness**

This Privacy Policy is effective as of February 1, 2009.  We reserve the right, at any time, to modify, alter, or update this policy, and any such modifications, alterations, or updates will be effective upon posting.  In the event we modify this Privacy Policy, your continued use of this Site will signify your acceptance of the modified Privacy Policy.

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy or the security on our Site, please [contact us](mailto:support@forexroot.com).

**Social Networking FAQ**

**Social Networking in General and the** **Forex Root** **Trader Social Network**

Social networks are on-line groups, networks or communities of people who share some common element(s) such as a particular interest, and are interested in exploring and discussing such interests with others on the internet. Social networking involves the on-line interaction of its members via multiple and various electronic formats, such as chat, messaging, email, video, voice chat, file sharing, blogging, discussion groups and so on.

A social network provides its members with many features, such as the ability to create and view profiles of other members who share commonalities. A social network also allows members to create personal profiles, potentially with fairly detailed information, as well as allow its members to engage in activities such as create personal blogs, share personal information and other applications that allow its members to help them to connect with other network members.

The **Forex Root** Trader Social Network is limited to individuals who are active forex traders, as described in the Terms of Use http://www.forexroot.com/terms-of-use. As with other social networks, members of the **Forex Root** Trader Social Network may create personal profiles, in this case with respect to their forex trading, and may share among other information, information on their forex trading activities and performance and their market views and trading strategies.

**Benefits to Social Networks**

A social network provides opportunities for its members to engage with other members and share information over the Internet and find other members on-line with similar interests.

**Risks to Social Networks**

Social networks are not without their risks, which are no different than any other on-line activity. With public spaces, or even within a closed social network community, the services can be used by anyone. There are risks as one does not truly know who the other members of the social network are. In addition, while **Forex Root** does its best to restrict access to your information, **Forex Root** has no control over what third parties with access to your information may do with it. For example, you may post certain personal information, but another member copies and publishes it.

When using social networks, you should take caution when posting your personal information as well as carefully consider the information you get from the social network. You should take care in trusting the information posted in a social network as it may be difficult to prevent members or the public at large from posting false or misleading information, including information in their personal profiles. Although **Forex Root** takes reasonable steps to regularly monitor the content of its site to identify and remove any misleading or otherwise fraudulent posts, and may ban a member for egregious or repeat violations, there is no assurance that we will detect all misleading or fraudulent posts, and members should not rely upon or assume the accuracy of information posted by other members and should make their own independent trading decisions.

In addition, be careful with personal information. Once you have posted your personal information to the internet, you have lost control over who will see it and how it will be used. Information you post or as contained in your profile can easily be copied and shared with thousands of others at the press of a button. In addition, when posting other materials, such as photos, you should take precaution as such information or pictures can be altered or distorted.

There is the potential for risk in using the **Forex Root** Trader Social Network stemming from the illegal or improper use of the social network by third parties who might, for example, post misleading information in an attempt to improperly influence trading decisions or find ways to copy and aggregate member profiles, collect personal financial information or copy personal content and use it for their own purposes.

Beware of files posted or clicking on executable files on social networks as social network sites provide an ideal and cost-efficient platform for the distribution of viruses, worms and bots, Trojans, spyware and more. Companies with a presence on these sites could be adversely affected.
